Now look friends, it must have happened many times
that whatever scooter or
bike you have purchased, its insurance
etc. must have expired and brother, I am
telling you literally that there are many such
companies which sell you insurance at a very high price
and brother, I am going to
tell you the direct method that how
you can get the
insurance of your bike or scooter
done at a very cheap rate within a few minutes while sitting at home.  Look,
whatever our dealership is or whatever
our offline or online agent is,
25 to 30% commission is already
included here which is
taken from your premium amount.  But friends, if you are
watching this video then we are going to
tell you the direct method here.
How you can get your insurance done
directly through a company.
But look, you should keep one thing in mind that
whenever you purchase insurance for your bike or scooter, then
while purchasing the insurance, we have to keep
three things in mind.  Basically
we have three types of insurance.   The first one is
our first party
insurance.  The second is third party
insurance and the third is our
comprehensive insurance.  If I
tell you this in terms of price, then the
cheapest insurance we have is our
third party insurance.
Our first party insurance is more expensive than third party insurance [laughs]
and the most expensive is
our comprehensive insurance.   Let me
tell you the difference between the three
so that you do
not face any problem while selecting insurance.  Look, let's assume that
I have taken
third party insurance for my bike or scooter.
Now I am going out on the road.
Why do we get insurance?  Firstly,
whenever we have an accident, God forbid an
accident should happen.  But whenever an accident happens,
our insurance company pays our insurance claim in that case.
So this became the first reason.  The second reason was
that the police etc. should not catch us and
issue a challan against us.  So look, under
this third party
insurance of yours, the police can never issue a challan against you
because you have already
purchased the insurance.  But you will
not get to see one thing here.  Let us assume that
if your bike or scooter hits another
scooter or any other pole.
And for example, if
your scooter was worth ₹1 lakh.
We suffered a loss of ₹10,000.  So,
if you have taken third party insurance of ₹10,000, then
you have to pay ₹10,000 from your pocket to get
it repaired.
But at the same time, if the person in front
was on a bike or scooter and you also
come here on a bike or scooter, then both of you
collide.  If you are involved in a collision, the
company will not pay you for the loss you suffer.
But whatever loss the other person has suffered,
your third party insurance
company
pays it to the other person.  But if you had
purchased first party insurance here, it would have been a
bit expensive.  So
what happens now is that even the police will not issue you a challan.
And if you assume that if
both of you collide, then the company will
pay the money to the other person but here
you will also be given a claim.  If you also
take your scooter or bike to your showroom and leave it there.  After that the
insurance agent comes and he will do his
complete investigation as to where and how much
loss has occurred and after that
if you have purchased first party insurance
then he will pass your claim
and after that whatever work you have to do will be done for
free.  But
if you have taken third party insurance then
brother, you will have to pay all this money
from your pocket.  And in our
comprehensive plan, there are
some parts in the comprehensive plan
like wear and tear
parts which are
not covered under our first party insurance.   That's
why we take a comprehensive plan here.
Even our smallest items are covered under the comprehensive plan.
You can take as many add-ons as you want here.
The more add-ons you take,
the more your premium keeps
increasing.  I believe that
either you should purchase third party insurance
or you should directly
purchase first party insurance here.  If your
bike is very old
and you feel that its value is
no longer there and you just
want to avoid challan etc. then you
can purchase third party insurance here.   Even
if your bike etc. does not run much,
in that case also your third
party insurance is sufficient.
But friends, if your bike
or scooter is in perfect condition, then in that
case you should take first party
insurance because the
loss caused to it is very high.
And if I tell you genuinely, there is
not much difference between these two insurances.  So friends, let me
tell you the full process once,
how you can get your
bike or scooter insured
directly through the company while sitting at home and
here we are going to use Ekko company
which does our insurance for us at the cheapest rate.
Basically, I will provide you the
direct link for getting insurance in the description box below.
By clicking there you will go directly to their official
website.  So friends, here
you can see that the
website I am going to tell you about for purchasing insurance
is apo.com.  If you
want its direct link, I will
put it in the description box below.  Now here you
can see that your insurance
starts at a very low rate.  Let me
quickly tell you what
you have to do to get insurance.  First of all you have to
enter the number of your bike or scooter
whichever is on your number plate.
After that you have to click on Simply View Prices.
Now here you will have to get your
brand or model verified.
As you can see here, we will have
many models.  You
can see as per your convenience which bike you have.
After that, the registration number of when you got the bike
registered will be
inside your RC.  You have to
basically select that year here.
After that you have to proceed.  After that friends,
he is asking
what is the status of your current policy?  The
first option we see is Not Expired.   That
means it has not expired yet.   The
policy is still lying in our current account.
Now it means that it is going to expire in two-three days.  something like that.
After that it says
expired in the last 90 days.   This
means that your policy will expire in 90 days.
And the third one is saying
that expiry is more than 90 days.  This means that it has been
more than 90 days since your policy
expired.  Look brother, if there are too many
, then you will have to get verification done here etc.  This
means that you will have to
take a photo etc. and upload it.
And you will have to follow the same process even if your policy has expired within 90 days.
If your policy has not expired
then you do not need to do anything.
You can also see a new policy for the same policy.
But if your policy has
expired then you will have to provide
proof here.  Because friend, let's assume that
my policy has expired.  There was
some damage to my car and
they made a policy and I should go and
claim it tomorrow.  So brother, things don't work like this.
First they will see whether your
car is completely safe or not.  Only then will
they allow you to buy insurance.
If my car is completely safe.
I will make a photo video and send it to them.
After that my policy will be implemented.
And if there is any damage from anywhere, they will
write a damage report saying that this was
already damaged.  If you claim it later, it will
not be given to you.
And brother, this happens everywhere.  Now here
you can see that my car has arrived here.
I am going to tell you the ID value also.
And brother, this is a very important
thing, listen to it carefully.
After that we are being asked
to select the tenure here.  1 year,
2 years or 3 years.  For how many years do you
want to take the policy?  But
before the policy, let me tell you the IDV value once.
IDV value is our
insured value.  That is, what will be the
total value of our car.
For example, you can see that our
₹61,100 will be our highest IDB
value and ₹32,900 will be our
lowest IDB value and our IDB
value is currently around 47,000, that is, in the middle.
Look, the meaning of IDV value is
that for example, if my car catches
fire, gets stolen, or gets
total lost, then in that case, the
company from which I am purchasing the insurance will pay
me only the IDV
value.  And if
you increase or decrease the IDV value, then the
amount in your insurance premium will also increase or decrease very slightly.
So brother,
I would say that you should keep your IDB
value very high so that even
if there is a total loss
or if due to any reason your vehicle gets
totally lost, then at least you will get
coverage of a higher amount.
That's why friends, I also
always keep my IDB value high.
After that I click on continue.
Now here I have to select for
how many years I want to take the policy.
Here you will see that you have a third
party plan and a comprehensive
plan.  I have already made it clear to you.
So now you will
not need to use much brain here.  The third party plan that is being given to us here is
for ₹714 and our
comprehensive plan is only for ₹13.  This
is the only difference between the two plans.
Whereas if I select a 2 year plan then the
comprehensive AMA
reaches and our third party plan
reaches ₹1428.  And similarly, your
3 year comprehensive plan will be ₹2843
and our third party plan will be
₹12142.  So brother, you should
see as per your convenience as to how many years'
plan you want to purchase.  Now friends, if
you finally see here, I have
selected my plan for one year.
I will not take the comprehensive plan right now.   Right now
I would like to take a third party plan here
because look, my bike etc. remains lying
empty in the house and when the
bike is not used that much then
why should I invest money in the first party here,
but if your bike or scooter is
used for daily running then you should
take a comprehensive plan here.
I would prefer this to you.  Now let me
tell you what all
we get to see in the comprehensive plan.
For example, in case of an accident,
if your vehicle is totally lost or
damaged, then here you will be covered for the
repair cost or replacement cost
if your bike is damaged due to an accident or if it is
damaged due to fire, then
you will be covered in that case also.
If there is theft, then
But make sure that
in case of theft, you should have both your keys with you.
After that, climate means
if there is a flood anywhere,
earthquake etc., something falls on your bike or
scooter, then
you will get a claim in that case.  If there is a third party
injury or death, that is, the third
party, the person in front of us, whom we
hit, or if anything happens, then a
claim is provided to him also by a company,
and the property of the third party
also, that is, the bike etc. of the person in front with whom
our bike etc. collided, will
also be provided a claim.
So friends, these were the
benefits of our comprehensive plan.  And
I will also tell you when these benefits will not be given to you.  Non-accidental
damage means if your tyre,
tube, engine etc. gets damaged, then
in this case you are not given cover for the damage etc.
And if you drive illegally
, that is, if you break the traffic law
or you
drive without a driving license or
if you drive after consuming alcohol or drunk etc., then
in that case
you will not be given any claim here.
You have to keep this in mind.
After that, let me tell you the benefits of third party
plans also.   For example, in case of
third party injury or
death,
coverage will be provided to him in that case also
and coverage is also provided to the property of the third party.
And what these people do not cover under the third party
plan is own bike damage, that is, if
our own bike gets damaged then
we will not get any coverage at all
and if you do illegal driving
then you will not get any coverage in that also.
So friends,
I am going to select my third party plan here.
So I select it and
click on continue.
After that, you will see here that we are being given
personal accidental cover.
If you already have it, you
can skip it if you want.  Otherwise, you can also get
₹15 lakh sum assured i.e. personal
extender cover for ₹350.   If
you want, you can also add it on.  It's
totally up to you.  It is basically optional.  Now
here you will see that you will have to enter some of your personal
details.  Like you have to give your full name
here.  You have to give your email ID
, mobile number, pin code
and if you have GST then this is optional.  If you want to
give, you can give.  Otherwise you
can also skip it.  Now here you
can see that
whatever details of the bike etc. we had entered in the review and details,
all the things have reached us.  You must check out
your ID value carefully here once.
And
you must also verify here which plan you are taking.
So let me quickly
process this payment.  Now friends,
here you can see that I am being asked to do it for
₹843.  I
quickly complete my payment here through Pay Phone or Google Pay.
Now friends, after completing the payment etc.,
you will also have to get your complete
KYC done here.  Look, any
person who has a bike or scooter has to
submit his PAN card and Aadhar card here.  And make sure that the
payment should also be made from his account.
And friends, this rule has been
implemented in all the companies.  Whether you take
your policy online or offline.  And the
rule has come into effect from July 1, 2023.  So
let us quickly
complete our KYC.  Now
friends, to get KYC done here,
you simply have to get your PAN card number verified.
After that, if
you want, you can also give your Aadhar card etc. as address proof.
Here we will
complete all the work through Digilocker only.  You
can see that first of all you have to enter your phone name and
government ID on this.  After that
you have to accept their terms and conditions
and click on the continue button.
After continuing, here
you have to
enter your PAN card number according to the government ID and here
you also have to enter your date of birth.
I complete both the things quickly.
After that I will click on the proceed button.
Now here
two options are being given for your document verification.  If
you want, you can get it done manually
or you
can also get your document verified through Digilocker.  Friends, we are going to
give our driving license here.  You
can see that
after selecting the driving license, now you have to
upload the driving license from your front side as well as
from the back side.
Here I simply
enable permissions for camera etc.  After that
I upload my driving license from the front side.
You can see here that it has been
uploaded.  I will simply
click on Use This Photo.  After that you
can see that almost all our work is complete.
Here you basically have to enter your city.
Gender has to be selected.
Male or female, whatever.  After that
you will also have to choose a relation here.  Let's assume
brother that whatever company is there in any case.
Look, this is a hypothetical case
that if some accident happens to you, then
whom should you contact in that case
?  So here I would like to
create Father.  First Name of Your Relation
and Last Name of Your Relation.  Now
complete both the details here.  After that
you have to finally click on the submit button.
Now friends, here you
can finally see that our KYC verification has been
successfully completed.
I did all the work in front of you.  Now
as soon as your KYC is verified, it is done
immediately, which means
after the payment is complete, your KYC is
verified and after that our policy is issued to
us and see, it
takes two to three minutes for your policy to be issued.
Here you can
see your policy in PDF format.
As you can see here, our
bike etc. is being shown.
You will also be able to see the dates when your policy is starting and when it is ending.  I will
blur this out for security reasons.
And here you are
given the option to download the policy.  Rest friend,
if you take your policy as a by any chance and
someday there is some damage etc.
and you want to claim for it, then to
claim it you will have to
talk to their customer care number and
whatever your claim is, an
attempt is made to settle it quickly here.
So I am recommending you to get one here
because brother it is a very
best application.  I myself get my
policies etc. done through this website.
So friends, this was the
complete process of getting your bike or scooter
insured.  Once you
comment, please tell me which bike you have
and for how much you are purchasing its policy.
Rest of the friends, see you in the
next video.